Register of the Constantine Maria Panunzio Papers, 1907-1947
Hoover Institution Archives
Constantine Maria Panunzio papers
1907-1947
XX077
Hoover Institution Archives
19 manuscript boxes and 1 oversize box (7.1 linear feet)
The Constantine Maria Panunzio papers contain significant materials relating to the Mussolini dictatorship in Italy and the aftermath of fascist rule in the country at the end of World War II. As a sociologist whose primary research focus was on the immigrant experience in the United States, Panunzio also retained a keen interest in political developments in his native Italy. This interest is reflected in the papers, which are almost exclusively concerned with the subject of Italian fascism. The papers include Panunzio's speeches and writings on Italian politics during the Mussolini period, as well as an extensive subject file on Italian fascism compiled by Panunzio. There are also other research materials on the same subject in the papers, and these include a large amount of clippings and excerpts from monographs. Additionally, the collection contains a considerable number of writings on fascist Italy by other authors.
Panunzio, Constantine Maria, 1884-1964
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical note
1884 October 25 Born, Molfetta, Italy
1912 Awarded M.A. degree, Wesleyan University
1914 Awarded Bachelor of Sacred Theology degree, Boston University School of Theology
1917-1918 YMCA general organizer, Italian front
1921 Author, Soul of an Immigrant
1925 Awarded Ph.D. degree, Brookings Graduate School of Economics and Government
1931-1951 Professor of sociology, University of California at Los Angeles
1961 Distinguished Alumnus award, Wesleyan University
1964 Died
Scope and Contents note
The Constantine Maria Panunzio papers contain significant materials relating to the Mussolini dictatorship in Italy and the aftermath of fascist rule in the country at the end of World War II. As a sociologist whose primary research focus was on the immigrant experience in the United States, Panunzio also retained a keen interest in political developments in his native Italy. This interest is reflected in the papers, which are almost exclusively concerned with the subject of Italian fascism. The papers include Panunzio's speeches and writings on Italian politics during the Mussolini period, as well as an extensive subject file on Italian fascism compiled by Panunzio. There are also other research materials on the same subject in the papers, and these include a large amount of clippings and excerpts from monographs. Additionally, the collection contains a considerable number of writings on fascist Italy by other authors.
Panunzio's original arrangement for the subject file on Italian fascism he compiled has been retained. The subject file includes numerous clippings, as well as some correspondence and writings by Panunzio. Panunzio's headings for the subject file cover a wide range of topics relating to the Mussolini period, including politics, the economy, education, and popular culture. The subject file contains a considerable amount of biographical information about Mussolini, as well as materials relating to the antifascist movement opposed to his dictatorship.
The additional series of research materials in the collection relating to fascist Italy (Other research materials relating to Italy under Mussolini) includes abstracts of articles, clippings, excerpts from serial issues, pamphlets, and monographs, as well as an extensive bibliography of articles and books compiled by Panunzio. The Writings by others series is comprised of numerous articles, most of which pertain to fascist Italy and to the Allied campaign in Italy during World War II. There are some articles in this series relating to Italian politics in the immediate post-World War II era.
The collection also contains correspondence from the time of World War II, letters to and from servicemen and civilians that were presumably to be used by Panunzio as the basis for a sociological study of wartime attitudes.
Arrangement Statement
The collection is organized into 9 series: Correspondence; Speeches and writings; Subject file on Italian fascism; Other research materials relating to Italy under Mussolini; Writings by others; World War II correspondence file; Photographs; Printed matter; and Memorabilia.
Mussolini, Benito, 1883-1945.; Partito nazionale fascista.; Antisemitism--Italy.; Fascism--Italy.; Italy--Politics and government--20th century.; Italy--Religion.; Italy.
- Correspondence, 1943
  - Latin Union for Democracy and Freedom, 1943 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Speeches and writings, 1927-1943
  - "How Fascism Came to Italy,", 1927 April (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - "Italy in Turmoil,", 1928 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Speech on fascism, 1928 January 20 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Speech on fascism, Delphian Club, Los Angeles, 1928 March 6 (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Article on Italy (fragment), 1935 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - "Fires under Italy's Boiling Pot,", 1930 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - "Present Day Disturbed Conditions in Italy in the Light of Italian Traits,", 1930 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - "Nationalistic Trends in Italian Education," notes for talk at Teachers' Institute, University of California at Los Angeles, 1932 December 19 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - "Liberal Italy," review of book by Benedetto Croce, 1935 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - "Homes for the Poor,", 1938 February 27 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - "Educational Ramparts,", 1938 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - "Facisting[sic] the Schools,", 1938 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - "Students Free and Slaves,", 1938 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - "Goals,", 1938 February (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - "Mundane Goals,", 1938 February (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - "Doom over Hollywood,", 1939 (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - "Italian Sociology,", 1940 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - "The Social Content of the Contemporary Italian Schoolbook,", 1940 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - "Social and Economic Conditions in Present Day Italy,", 1941 February 12 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - "Fascist Education', 1941 February 24 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - "Conditions in Italy Today,", 1942 (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - "Toward a Free Democratic Italy,", 1942 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - "Italian Americans, Fascism, and the War,", 1942 Summer (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - "La bancarotta del fascismo,", 1942 September 28 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - "Italy of Yesterday, Today and Tomorrow,", 1943 October 1 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - "Una curación no basta; precisa una operación,", 1943 December 15 (Box-folder 1: 27)
- Subject file on Italian fascism, 1912-1947
  - Outline of topics, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - American fascist (Kenneth Scott), 1938 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Antifascism, 1928-1943
    - Clippings, 1929-1943 (Box-folder 1: 30)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Antifascists, 1925-1943
    - Clippings, 1925-1943 (Box-folder 1: 32)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Anti-semitism and racism, 1933-1941
    - Clippings, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 1: 34)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1933-1938 (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - As Italians saw the U.S., 1928-1938 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Banco Commerciale Italiana, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Battle of wheat, 1931-1939 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - Books Italians read in 1938 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - "Bread, Wine, and Taxes,", 1941 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Broadcasts in Italian, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 6-10)
  - Centro Italiano di Studi Americani, 1937 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Church vs. State, 1928-1938
    - Clippings, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 2: 12-13)
    - Writing and notes, 1929 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Cinema and film, 1934-1938
    - Clippings, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Programs, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Transcribed articles, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - Colonies, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - Democracy under fascism, 1938 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "Doom over Hollywood,", 1937-1942 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Economic life in Italy, 1925-1941
    - Clippings, 1926-1938
      - 1926-1934 (Box-folder 3: 7)
      - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Correspondence and official forms, 1929-1934 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1925-1941
      - 1925-1937 (Box-folder 3: 10)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 3: 11)
      - 1937-1941 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - Outline and references, 1937 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - Education, 1928-1941
    - Clippings, 1932-1938 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1929-1941 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - Writings, 1928-1934 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  - Fascism in 1925 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Fascism in theory and practice, 1927-1941
    - Clippings, 1928-1938 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1927-1934 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - Writings, 1937-1941 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Fascist activities outside Italy, 1928-1942
    - Clippings, 1920-1937 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1942 (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Notes, 1928-1942 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Writings, 1930-1942 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - Fascist finance, 1932-1942 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Fascist mottoes, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - Foreign policy, 1938 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - Foreign students in Italy, 1938 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - Free Italy movement, 1943 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - Giustizia e Libertà, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - Hitler in Italy, 1938 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - Housing and land, 1938 (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - Il Duce (Benito Mussolini), 1938 (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - Imperialism, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - Italian militarism, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Italian monarchy, 1938-1944
    - Clippings, 1938-1944 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1938-1940 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Writing, 1940 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Italian personalities, 1925-1938 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Italian prisoners of war in the U.S., 1945 (Box-folder 5: 6)
  - Italians in America, 1921-1930 (Box-folder 5: 7)
  - Italy
    - 1920-1921, 1920-1942 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Italy-Axis relations, 1931-1938 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Italy-Russia relations, 1928-1944
    - Clippings, 1928-1944 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Lawyers' program, 1938 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - March on Rome, 1930 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Mazzini Society, 1941-1943
    - Los Angeles, 1941-1942
      - Correspondence, 1941-1942 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - Flyer and ticket, 1941 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - New York, 1941-1943
      - Clippings, 1943 (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Mostra Augustea della Romanità (commemoration of Emperor Augustus), 1937 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Mussolini, Benito, 1925-1941
    - Clippings, 1925-1941 (Box-folder 6: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1928 (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Serial issues, 1936-1937 (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Speeches, 1934-1937 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Population, 1929-1943
    - Clippings, 1929-1939 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1937-1943 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Post-war reconstruction, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 6: 14)
  - Protestantism in Italy, 1912-1938 (Box-folder 6: 15)
  - Production, trade, and prices, 1932-1939
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1937-1939 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Menus, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - Receipts, 1932-1938 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
  - Radio, 1938 (Box-folder 7: 5)
  - Recreational activities, 1933-1937 (Box-folder 7: 6)
  - Repatriation of Italian refugees, 1943-1944
    - Clippings, 1943 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 7: 8)
  - Republican Italy, 1947 (Box-folder 7: 9)
  - Resistance organizations, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 7: 10)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1929-1945
    - Announcements, 1929-1944 (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - Clippings, 1929-1944 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - Correspondence, 1929-1945 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Curriculum vitae, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - Petition, 1931 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Questions asked at lecture, 1944 (Box-folder 7: 16)
  - School books and education under Mussolini, 1941 (Box-folder 7: 17-18)
  - Sforza, Carlo, 1928-1944
    - Clippings, 1928-1944 (Box-folder 8: 1)
    - Correspondence, 1928-1943 (Box-folder 8: 2)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1920-1928 (Box-folder 8: 3)
    - Speech, 1943 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Statistics, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Tarchiani, Alberto, 1945
    - Clippings, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 6)
    - Correspondence, 1945 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Theater, 1921-1938 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Tourism, 1935-1938 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - University life in Italy, 1921 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Women in Italy under fascism, 1930-1938
    - Clippings, 1933-1938 (Box-folder 8: 11)
    - Excerpts from monographs, 1930-1938 (Box-folder 8: 12)
    - Writing, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - World War I, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Youth movement, 1933-1938 (Box-folder 8: 15)
- Other research materials relating to Italy under Mussolini, 1921-1946
  - Abstracts of articles, 1929-1931 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Bibliography, 1925-1941
    - Articles in the Christian Science Monitor, 1933-1938
      - 1934-1938 (Box-folder 8: 17)
      - 1934-1937 (Box-folder 8: 18)
      - 1933-1935 (Box-folder 9: 1-2)
    - Articles in The New York Times, 1928-1935
      - 1928-1935 (Box-folder 9: 3)
      - 1934-1935 (Box-folder 9: 4-5)
      - 1933 (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Articles in various U.S. publications, 1925-1938
      - 1925-1937 (Box-folder 9: 7)
      - 1927-1938 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Books published in Germany, 1924-1933 (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Books published in Italy, 1930-1938 (Box-folder 10: 2-3)
    - Books published in Spain, 1930-1936 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Books published in the United States, 1927-1941 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Book announcements and catalogs, 1921-1938 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Book reviews, 1925-1944 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Clippings, 1926-1946
    - 1926-1927 (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - 1928-1930 (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - 1931-1932 (Box-folder 10: 10)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 10: 11)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 11: 1-3)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 11: 4-7)
    - 1934 (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - 1935 (Box-folder 12: 2-7)
    - 1937 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - 1938 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - 1938 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 1939-1940 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - 1943 (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - 1944 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
    - 1945-1946 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Excerpts from serial issues, pamphlets, and monographs, 1922-1940
    - Christian Science Monitor, 1932-1935
      - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 13: 8)
      - 1934 (Box-folder 13: 9-10)
      - 1935 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Commerce Reports, 1925-1940
      - 1925-1926 (Box-folder 14: 1)
      - 1938-1939 (Box-folder 14: 2)
      - 1940 (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Current History, 1925-1933
      - 1925 (Box-folder 14: 4)
      - 1926 (Box-folder 14: 5)
      - 1931-1933 (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1932 (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Foreign Policy Association pamphlets, 1927 (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - Foreign Policy Reports, 1931 (Box-folder 14: 9)
    - Haider, Carmen, Capital and Labor under Fascism, 1930 (Box-folder 14: 10-11)
    - International Conciliation, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 14: 12)
    - Italian sources, 1933-1938
      - 1933-1936 (Box-folder 14: 13)
      - 1937 (Box-folder 14: 14-15)
      - 1938 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
    - The Living Age, 1932 (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - The New York Times, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Survey Graphic, 1927 (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Tittoni, Tomasso, Modern Italy, 1922 (Box-folder 15: 6)
- Writings by others, 1907-1946
  - Abad, C. H., 1931 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Alvarez del Vayo, Julio, 1940 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1928 (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Baldanzi, George, 1945 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Bauer, Ludwig, 1932 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Beals, Carleton, 1921 (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - Bedel, Maurice, 1929 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Bellini, Mario, 1945 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Bess, Demaree, 1943 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Binkley, Robert C., 1930 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Bogardus, Emory S., 1933 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Borgese, G. A., 1938-1945 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1930 (Box-folder 15: 19)
  - Brown, David, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - Brown, E. Francis, 1933 (Box-folder 15: 21)
  - Beull, Raymond Leslie, 1933 (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - Bullitt, William C., 1944 (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - Bunn, Henry W., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 24)
  - Burns, Cecil Delisle, 1928 (Box-folder 15: 25)
  - Busch, Noel F., 1944 (Box-folder 15: 26)
  - Cibelli, Enrico, 1938 (Box-folder 15: 27)
  - Corti, Lucia, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 28)
  - Cowley, Malcom, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 29)
  - Daly, John, 1944 (Box-folder 15: 30)
  - Day, Adam, 1929 (Box-folder 15: 31)
  - De Santillana, Giorgio, 1943 (Box-folder 15: 32)
  - Dell, Robert, 1934 (Box-folder 15: 33)
  - Dennis, Alfred P., 1920 (Box-folder 16: 1)
  - Deutschman, Paul E., 1944 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Di Marzo, Salvatore, 1932 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Einaudi, Mario, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 4)
  - Ellery, Eloise, 1927-1931 (Box-folder 16: 5)
  - Elliott, Randle, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 6)
  - Elliott, W. Y., 1933 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Eulau, Heinz, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Evola, Julius, 1936 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Fernsworth, Lawrence, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Flanner, Janet, 1942 (Box-folder 16: 11)
  - Flannery, Harry W., 1943 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Gellhorn, Martha, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Gentile, Giovanni, 1928 (Box-folder 16: 14)
  - Gervasi, Frank, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Gini, Corrado, 1914-1931 (Box-folder 16: 16)
  - Grandi, Dino, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 17)
  - Haines, C. Grove, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 18)
  - Hamburger, Philip, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 19)
  - Hart, B. H. Liddell, 1934 (Box-folder 16: 20)
  - Hazen, N. William, 1940 (Box-folder 16: 21)
  - Hearley, John, 1930 (Box-folder 16: 22)
  - Hincks, Marcelle Azra, 1938 (Box-folder 16: 23)
  - Hunter, Paul, 1945 (Box-folder 16: 24)
  - Jouvenel, Henry de, 1927 (Box-folder 16: 25)
  - Lang, Daniel, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 26)
  - Lanius, Charles, 1943 (Box-folder 16: 27)
  - Laves, Walter H. C., 1927 (Box-folder 16: 28)
  - Lee, Clark, 1944 (Box-folder 16: 29)
  - Lee, Rose, 1930 (Box-folder 16: 30)
  - Lewin, Evans, 1927 (Box-folder 16: 31)
  - Lingelbach, William E., 1931-1935 (Box-folder 16: 32)
  - Lussu, Emilio, 1930 (Box-folder 16: 33)
  - Marcu, Valeriu, 1929 (Box-folder 17: 1)
  - Marraro, Howard R., 1933-1946 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - Menna, Emma, 1936 (Box-folder 17: 3)
  - Michie, Allan A., 1944 (Box-folder 17: 4)
  - Milano, Paolo, 1943 (Box-folder 17: 5)
  - Moravia, Alberto, 1946 (Box-folder 17: 6)
  - Motherwell, Hiram, 1929 (Box-folder 17: 7)
  - Mussolini, Benito, 1932-1939 (Box-folder 17: 8)
  - Nadeau, Ludovic, 1926 (Box-folder 17: 9)
  - Nenni, Pietro, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Nitti, Francesco, 1928-1930 (Box-folder 17: 11)
  - Pacciardi, Randolfo, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 12)
  - Painton, Frederick C., 1945 (Box-folder 17: 13)
  - Palmer, Gretta, 1945 (Box-folder 17: 14)
  - Pei, Mario A., 1928 (Box-folder 17: 15)
  - Poggioli, Renato, 1934 (Box-folder 17: 16)
  - Putnam, Samuel, 1930 (Box-folder 17: 17)
  - Ratta, Amedeo, 1938 (Box-folder 17: 18)
  - Raymond, Allen, 1944 (Box-folder 17: 19)
  - Rea, Gene, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 17: 20)
  - Reed, Macon, Jr., 1944 (Box-folder 17: 21)
  - Rendi, Renzo, 1940 (Box-folder 17: 22)
  - Reynolds, Minnie J., 1907 (Box-folder 17: 23)
  - Rocco, Alfredo, 1926 (Box-folder 17: 24)
  - Rockwell, W. W., 1929 (Box-folder 17: 25)
  - Rossi, Mario, 1945 (Box-folder 17: 26)
  - Russell, Charles Edward, 1925 (Box-folder 17: 27)
  - Salvemini, Gaetano, 1927-1946
    - 1927-1936 (Box-folder 17: 28)
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 17: 29)
    - 1944-1946 (Box-folder 17: 30)
  - Sauerwein, Jules, 1928 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Savorgnan, Franco, 1937 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Seldes, George, 1934 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Semcourt, Robert, 1926 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Sergio, Lisa, 1943 (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Sforza, Carlo, 1927-1943
    - 1927-1929 (Box-folder 18: 6)
    - 1930-1943 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Silone, Ignazio, 1946 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Silva, José, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Spencer, Henry R., 1932 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Steiner, H. Arthur, 1939 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Sturzo, Luigi, 1943-1945 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Toja, Guido, 1932 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Tallone, Nicolo, 1928 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - Toscanini, Arturo, 1943 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - Trentin, Silvio, 1929 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Trotsky, Leon, 1944 (Box-folder 18: 17)
  - Valiani, Leo, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 18: 18)
  - Valori, Aldo, 1937 (Box-folder 18: 19)
  - Vigne, J. J., 1931 (Box-folder 18: 20)
  - Villari, Luigi, 1926 (Box-folder 18: 21)
  - Viton, Albert, 1938 (Box-folder 18: 22)
  - Ward, Lois B., 1939 (Box-folder 18: 23)
  - Wilson, Edmund, 1945 (Box-folder 18: 24)
  - Wilstach, Paul, 1928 (Box-folder 18: 25)
  - Winner, Percy, 1930 (Box-folder 18: 26)
  - Wright, Charles Will, 1934 (Box-folder 18: 27)
- World War II correspondence file, 1941-1943
  - Crawford, Donald J., 1941-1943
    - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Letters from combat areas, 1940-1942
    - 1939-1941 (Box-folder 19: 3)
    - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - Letters to and from servicemen, 1941-1942
    - 1941-1942 (Box-folder 19: 5)
    - 1942 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1942-1943
    - 1942 (Box-folder 19: 7)
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 19: 8)
- Photographs, 1937
  - 1 print depicting Benito Mussolini, 1937 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - 8 prints depicting mass rallies and ceremonies in Italy, 1937 (Box-folder 19: 10)
- Printed matter, 1925-1939
  - Leaflets, 1930 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Postcards, 1925-1939
    - 3 cards depicting Adolf Hitler and Bentiro Mussolini, 1938 (Box-folder 20: 2)
    - 38 cards depicting scenes in Italy, 1925-1939 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Poster, 1937 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Serial issues, 1928-1939
    - Le Flambeau, 1929 June (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - La Giovine Italia, 1939 July 22 (Box-folder 20: 6)
    - La Lotta Umana, 1928 September 30 (Box-folder 20: 7)
    - Res Publica, 1931 December (Box-folder 20: 8)
    - Il Settebello, 1937 November 6-27 (Box-folder 20: 9)
    - Umanità Nova, 1932 October 20 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Memorabilia, 1917-1937
  - 5 medals issued by Italy, Austria, and the United States, 1917-1920 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - 1 medallion issued by the YMCA and American Expeditionary Forces, 1918 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - 12 coins issued by Italy, Vatican City, and San Marino, 1918-1937 (Box-folder 20: 13)